<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title/><link>/</link><description>Recent content on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-6/practical-sound-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-6/practical-sound-design/</guid><description>Guns We can&amp;rsquo;t go out to a range and record ourselves, so our next best thing is to piece together something realistic from sound effects libraries. It&amp;rsquo;s our job to take these recordings and to make them sound like what people think guns sound like. More exciting and explosive, instead of pops like firecrackers.
We can break the sound down into the following elements transient, body, thump, tail, foley or mechanical sounds, and bullet/shells.</description></item><item><title/><link>/pages/lectures/week-8/coding-audio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-8/coding-audio/</guid><description>First create an empty GameObject called AudioManger and add another GameObject as a child called Clickable Source. Add an audio source to the ClickableSource GameObject. Also add two more GameObjects to the AudioManger, one that plays music and one that plays ambience.
Create a play sound script with this code:
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 public class PlayASound : MonoBehaviour { public AudioSource MusicSource; public AudioClip MusicClip; // Start is called before the first frame update void Start() { PlaySound(MusicSource, MusicClip); } void PlaySound(AudioSource source, AudioClip clip) { source.</description></item><item><title>Adding footsteps</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-11/footsteps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-11/footsteps/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ll build a footstep system for our environment that has the following properties:
player is grounded match player&amp;rsquo;s speed random + no repeats material specific Our materials in this project are stone, dirt/grass, and wooden floors. We can check if a player is on the terrain and if the player is in a building. If they&amp;rsquo;re inside then they are standing on a wooden floor. Then we can assume that if they player is outside, then they&amp;rsquo;re on stone or on dirt.</description></item><item><title>Animations</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-9/animations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-9/animations/</guid><description>Understanding Animations First open the animation window by going to window -&amp;gt; animation -&amp;gt; animation. Then add it to the dock next to the console window.
Next create a cube and reset the transform so it&amp;rsquo;s in the center of the scene. Create three more cubes to make a sign. Add a material to each cube to give the sign some color.
Select the sign and create a new animation clip.</description></item><item><title>Final Mix</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-10/final-mix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-10/final-mix/</guid><description>Open the SampleScene. Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re viewing the scene in 3D. Drag the AudioManager GameObject to your prefabs folder if you haven&amp;rsquo;t done it already in an earlier lesson.
Open the PointAndClick scene and drag in your AudioManager prefab. Only do this if you needed to import the AudioManager. If you already had it just leave it there. The AudioManger should have the MusicSource, AmbiSource and Clickable Source GameObjects.
Fix your AudioSources in your Thirdperson prefab, they won&amp;rsquo;t stay in when you add it to a new scene.</description></item><item><title>Game Sound Database</title><link>/pages/database/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/database/</guid><description/></item><item><title>intro to unity</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-2-the-roll-of-audio-in-interactive-and-immersive-environments/wednesday-9-1/intro-to-unity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-2-the-roll-of-audio-in-interactive-and-immersive-environments/wednesday-9-1/intro-to-unity/</guid><description>Start with a new scene
Explore the main windows
Hierarchy window scene view inspector project game view play mode navigate using toolbar
Pan: Select the Hand tool in the Toolbar, and click and drag in the Scene view to move your view. Zoom: Holding Alt (Windows) or Option (macOS), right-click and drag in the Scene view to zoom. Orbit: Holding Alt (Windows) or Option (macOS), left-click and drag to orbit around the current pivot point.</description></item><item><title>Player movements</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-9/locomotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-9/locomotion/</guid><description>Setup first person character Download this package and import it into your project. Create a new scene, name it Locomotion, and doubleclick to open it.
Add a plane to your scene and reset its location to the origin. Next add the first person character prefab. Move it so its visible above the plane. Now you delete the other camera and add the pressure pad prefab to the scene.
On the first person control script add a character controller by selecting the dropdown menu next to CC and choosing Firstperson (character controller).</description></item><item><title>Projects</title><link>/pages/projects/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/projects/</guid><description>Project 1 Add sounds to 5 GameObjects in pyramid tutorial project. Move them with the scripts you already had and listen to how the doppler effect works.
Project 2 Use sounds freesound.org to replace the sounds of the FPS project. You may need to edit the sounds from freesound, or manipulate them. Experiment with filters and effects.
Add another room using the tutorial. Add an enemy using the tutorial. Give the new enemy some sounds.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>/pages/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/resources/</guid><description>Sound Designers Mike Niederquell Lost Chocolate Lab Joe Thwaites Javier Zumer Websites Gamasutra - Audio Podcasts Game Audio Podcast Immersive Audio Podcast Software Game Engines Unity Unreal Engine bitsy Audio Engines FMOD Wwise 3d Audio Steam Audio - Immersive Audio Solutions For games and VR Tutorials Sound Librarian Conferences Interactive Music Symposium - Thursday, August 26th, 12pm - 6pm GameSoundCon - November 8-10, 2021 Online Audio Developer Conferece - November 15th &amp;amp; 16th - In-Person/Online Conference in London - November 19th - Online Workshops Example from last year Game Developers Conference - March 21-25, 2022 | San Francisco, CA</description></item><item><title>Schedule</title><link>/pages/schedule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/schedule/</guid><description>table { border-collapse: collapse; width: 100%; } tr { border-bottom: 1px solid #ccc; } th { text-align: left; } } Week Date Topics, Assignments, Quizzes, Tests, Deadlines 1 8/23, 8/25, 8/27 Monday 8/23 Me - Dr. Carson Class introductions Name? Class year? Where are you from? What&amp;rsquo;s your favorite game or movie? Syllabus Perusall signup I will assign readings, videos, or podcasts through Perusall.</description></item><item><title>Sun Temple Ambient SFX</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-11/sun-temple-ambient-sfx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-11/sun-temple-ambient-sfx/</guid><description>Setup Download some ambient SFX loops . These are already loops, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to edit them.
Add a GameObject as a child of the camera to hold some audio sources. Add an audio source and add the wind sound to as its clip.
Random crickets Add another audio source to play the cricket sound but set its volume to 0. We will create a script to fade in and fade out this sound randomly.</description></item><item><title>Sun Temple Fire SFX</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-11/sun-temple-fire-sfx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-11/sun-temple-fire-sfx/</guid><description>Setup We&amp;rsquo;re now going to add sounds to a more complex game environment, the Sun Temple. Go to the asset store and download the project . Download and import it into to your project.
To get an error to go away I had to edit the MinDrawer.cs file. I just removed the reference to using UnityEngine.PostProcessing; and it seems to be working. If you scene is running very slowly try to turn off the post processing effects in the post processing profile.</description></item><item><title>Syllabus</title><link>/pages/syllabus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/syllabus/</guid><description>Course Prefix, Number, and Title: DAD 422 Audio Production III Advanced Techniques and MIDI Music
AKA Introduction to Immersive Game Audio
Credits: 3
University Name: Dakota State University
Academic Term/Year: Fall 2021
Last date to Drop and receive 100% refund: September 2nd, 2021
Last date to Withdraw and earn a grade of &amp;lsquo;W&amp;rsquo;: November 5th, 2021
Course Meeting Time and Location: MWF 1:00 pm – 2:40 pm TCB 209
Instructor Information: Name: Tate Carson Office: TCB 305 Email Address: Tate.</description></item><item><title>Third person movements</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-10/third-person-locomotion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-10/third-person-locomotion/</guid><description>Disable the Firstperson GameObject by un-checking it in the inspector. Drag the third person prefab into your Hierarchy. Create a new script inside the scripts/audio folder called ThirdPersonLocomotionSound. Use the same code from your first person script but remove the capability to measure footstep frequency. Add this script to Ellen. Make the AudioClip variables match this:
1 2 3 4 public AudioClip[] FootstepSFX; public AudioClip[] LandSFX; public AudioClip[] JumpEmote; public AudioClip[] LandEmote; Also make sure you have four functions to play each sound.</description></item><item><title>UI sounds</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-10/ui-sounds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-10/ui-sounds/</guid><description>Setup Create a new scene in the scene folder named UI and open it. In Unity UI GameObjects exist inside of Canvas GameObjects. Create a button GameObject and see how its inside of Canvas. Toggle 2D view in the scene pane. This allows you to see the Canvas like a player will. Set the aspect ratio of the Game pane to 16:9. Place the button in the center of the Canvas if it isn&amp;rsquo;t already.</description></item><item><title>What is immersive audio?</title><link>/pages/lectures/week-1/monday-8-23/immersive-spatial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/pages/lectures/week-1/monday-8-23/immersive-spatial/</guid><description>Think about your favorite game or movie. What about the sounds creates a feeling of being correct or realistic? Or more simply, what do we need to recreate from real life sounds in our virtual world?
Using what we learned from the video lets analyze the following games.
Questions How do games use sound to evoke place or actions? Adaptive audio level 1: an event leads to a sound Adaptive audio level 2: replace or modify sound depending on variables Game Audio Examples Joe Thwaites - Sackboy explainer Mike Niederquell videos Transistor - Super Giant Games</description></item></channel></rss>